A Software Engineer and also a proud Tech evangelist fueled by her passion to promote Science, Technology, Engineering, and Mathematics (STEM) among women in South Sudan and to as many communities as she can reach. Paith's concentration lie in Artificial Intelligence and natural language processing to improve people's experiences with their devices, and to make the people, products, and services that are important to life more accessible for everyone.

Work History

2017-06 -Current

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

UNITED HEALTH GROUP

- My role combines knowledge and experience from cognitive science, human factors, human-computer interaction design, and systems engineering. As well as its multidisciplinary opportunities with data analysis, python design, and evaluation of complex systems of people and technology in the healthcare space.
- Actively driving the global process of developing of our common company values, vision and mission.
- Supporting teams with focus on creating common tools, methods, techniques and systems that have significant impact the healthcare space.
- Designing and developing our measuring system to monitor the adoption and evolution of cultural issues throughout the organization.

2018-01 -2018-09

Chief of Staff

United Health Group, Minneapolis, MN

- Champion the set strategic initiatives for the organization and managing special projects across departments, like new frameworks or business models, restructuring, or business reviews.
- I leverage exceptional organizational and people skills to Influence, facilitate, orchestrate, and provide frameworks and effectively act as the central contact for all business communications.

2017-06 -2018-11

BUSINESS ANALYST

UNITED HEALTH GROUP

- Business Analyst for Optum's End User Technology organization.
- My focus was defining the Sharepoint application problem by conferring with data feed owners, building teams; evaluating procedures, migrating sites and processes using lean methodologies.

2019-10 -Current

MENTOR

Coder Dojo North Dakota, Minneapolis, MN

- I volunteer as a mentor at CoderDojo Twin Cities and as a mentor I am supportive first and foremost to children 8 to 17 year olds.
- I introduce kids to my knowledge of Python and Jupyter Notebook to not only engage them but

Paith Philemon

Software Engineer

Contact

Address

Minneapolis, MN, 55427

Phone

(515) 318-1344

E-mail

paithmp@gmail.com

LinkedIn

.com/in/paithphilemon/

Skills

UNIX. Linux. Raspberry Pi

Data Analysis

Data Modeling

Business Management

Microsoft Office

Python

Data Analysis

Data Modeling

Software

Data Science/Analysis

Programming

Jupyter Notebooks

Python

Languages

Arabic

Dinka

Swahil

English

Education

2012-05 - Bachelor's of Science: Management Information Systems

Iowa State University - Ames, IA

2014-05 - Bachelor's of Arts: Liberal Arts And Sciences
2017-01 lowa State University - Ames, IA

Accomplishments

 FOUNDER | THE FUTURIST ACADEMY The Futurist Academy is working to reshape the future. We leverage the latest technology and innovative ideas to mold a future of self-empowerment. With our platform, educators will be able to host their creative teaching solutions, styles, and agendas. At Futurist Academy, we believe that as long as you are Learning, Creating and Sharing your knowledge you become the Future. It is a network of students creating program of communities to leverage the latest technology and apply it through various methods such as workshops and hosted external events. Build skills in technology and digital media through which Futurists can innovate creative ideas to champion their advocacy. Explain, Teach, Inspire the Community.

Certifications

2018-05 UDACITY NANODEGREE Introduction to Programming 2019-01 UDACITY NANODEGREE Become a Data Scientist 2020-05 UDACITY NANODEGREE Data Analytics

Interests

Photography Traveling